# Rocio Galvan

rocio.galvan24@gmail.com | 757-266-6892 | Raleigh, NC 27529 <u>LinkedIn</u>: http://www.linkedin.com/in/rocio-galvan | <u>Github</u>: https://github.com/Ro-Galvan <u>Portfolio</u>: https://ro-galvan.github.io/portfolio/

# **Professional Summary**

Full Stack Web Developer looking to leverage over 10 years of fast-paced logistics, management, and customer service experience. Managing strict deadlines and communicating between departments and timezones is my speciality. Being resourceful and efficient will be at the forefront of my work in producing user friendly web apps.

## **Technical Skills**

Frontend: HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap, Bulma, Tailwind, Third-Party APIs Backend: MySQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, Handlebars, Server-Side APIs

Tools: GitHub, Heroku, Visual Studio

# **Projects**

Housable | https://github.com/devonfaria/housable | https://hidden-earth-95543.herokuapp.com/

- Helps you find a trustworthy person to watch your house, pets, plants while you are away
- Responsibilities: Handled the View portion of the Model View Controller and helped styled with CSS
- Tools/Languages: Node JS, MySQL2, Sequelize, Express, Handlebars, BCrypt, Dotenv

HobbyBox | https://github.com/jacksonnorris/hobby-box | https://agile-plateau-31401.herokuapp.com/

- Ships hobby-related products that change monthly and lets you select from 6 categories to keep it fresh
- Responsibilities: Worked on the client side: utils folder, debugged and styled the about me page
- Tools/Languages: React, Express, Apollo Client, GraphQL, Node JS, Progressive Web Applications, Flowbite CSS, Tailwind CSS, Cloudinary, Stripe, JWT Token, MongoDB, Mongoose, BCrypt, Web Vitals, Concurrently

# **Work Experience**

## AIR EXPORT AGENT

Expeditors | Raleigh, NC | 03/2021 - 01/2022

- Engaged customers to determine shipping needs & gathed compliance docs
- Managed all of the air export accounts for the Raleigh, NC branch
- Submitted customs export filings and verified/entered rates before invoicing
- Coordinated with overseas agents for rates, new requests and approvals
- Cross trained on ocean export process & temperature controlled shipments

## Assistant Manager

Lidl | Raleigh, NC & Virginia Beach, VA | **03/2020 - 03/2021** 

- Completed intensive 4 month training leading up to a final test and passed on first attempt
- Managed store operations by prioritizing tasks & aligning them to individual strengths, organizing breaks, driving shelf-stocking speeds, solving customer issues all while completing my own tasks
- Upheld quality standards by providing feedback, coaching or praising 21 team members
- Placed orders based on sales analytics & maintained system by fixing inventory discrepancies

## **CUSTOMER SERVICE OFFICER**

Holcim | Melbourne, Australia | 03/2018 - 09/2018

 Precisely input phone/email orders and entered into dispatch spreadsheet and system, taking care both matched 100% to avoid costly and time consuming errors

- Liaised hourly with construction engineers, quarries, dispatchers, truckers and account managers on new orders and followed up on existing ones
- Initiated and helped create an improved aggregate product spreadsheet to include sizes, colors, quarry availability, alternate names and special notes of each materia

#### **GUEST SERVICE AGENT**

Lizard Island Resort | Lizard Island, Australia | 09/2017 - 02/2018

- Went above and beyond to ensure memorable experiences were created at a luxury 5-star resort
- Greeted guests at airport and delivered a detailed point of interests tour in a 8 seater buggy, while engaging them
- Part of a collaborative team effort in triple checking guest reservation files for a flawless check-in
- · Created daily flight manifests and coordinated car transfers to and from the island for each guest

# **GUEST SERVICE AGENT**

Pegasus Apart'Hotel | Melbourne, Australia | **03/2017 – 08/2017** 

- Efficiently and rapidly checked guests in/out of a 275 room, 4-star hotel while remaining friendly
- Proactively addressed guests' requests and complaints in a positive and expeditious manner
- Verified reservation details transferred correctly from third party websites to our system

## **EXPORT PREMIERE REPRESENTATIVE-VIP**

CMA-CGM | Norfolk, VA | 01/2015 - 12/2016

- Oversaw export bookings & documentation for 5 premiere customers like Weber grill and Nestlé
- Interpreted customer specific contracts for queries about rates, routes and surcharges
- Verified loading appointments were adhered to and containers made railroad and vessel cutoffs
- Liaised with HQ, overseas offices, trade, sales, intermodal, and customers to resolve issues
- Maintained bi-weekly customer calls to ensure smooth daily operations

#### INBOUND VESSEL COORDINATOR

CMA-CGM | Norfolk, VA | **09/2013 - 01/2015** 

- Meticulously completed 22 steps every 2 weeks and saw the vessel through from start to finish
- Sent arrival notices & ensured documents, payment, & Customs clearance were received prior to release
- Ensured releases and free time were in place at ports & rail to avoid charges to the customer or service failure

# Education

# The University of North Carolina at Charlotte

Full-Stack Developer Certificate, 02/2022 -05/2022

Online- Full-Time

# The University of North Carolina at Greensboro

Bachelor of Science in Business Administration , 2008-2012 Greensboro, NC

# Università Carlo Cattaneo

Exchange Student, 02/2011 - 06/2011

Castellanza, Italy